I. Feinberg, Robert Arbitration Records 5548
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
I. Robert Feinberg Arbitration Records
1925-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Feinberg, I. Robert
5548
43 cubic feet
43 linear ft.
Case files, decisions.
Arbitration awards, decisions and related documents.
3336821
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Jeff Mintz, May 14, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Feinberg was a lawyer, arbitrator, mediator, and adjunct provessor of law at New York University.
Irving Robert Feinberg was the managing partner in the New York law firm of Guggenheimer and Untermyer at the time of his death. Feinberg was graduate of New York University (1932) and the NYU Law School (1934) and served his alma mater as an adjunct professor of law. Feinberg's primary career interest was labor arbitration. He served as assistant general counsel and chairman of the Appeals Committee of the National War Labor Board from 1943-1945, as vice chairman of the New York Regional War Labor Board in 1945, and as chairman of the Enforcement Commission of the National Wage Stabilization Commission in 1951-1952. Impartial chairman for the fur industry since 1968, Feinberg served also on arbitration panels for the Actors' Equity Association and the League of New York Theaters, the NYC Board of Education and the United Federation of Teachers, panels in the aircraft and shipping industries, and others.
---
Born January 3, 1912. Attended New York University (B.S., 1932, J.D., 1934); New York University Law Graduate School (1935).
Formerly assistant general counsel, National War Labor Board, 1942-1945; chairman, Appeals Committee, National War Labor Board, 1945; Vice-Chairman, War Labor Board, 2nd Region (1945); Adjunct Assistant Professor of Law, New York University Law School, 1952-; public and panel member, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, American Arbitration Association, and New York State Mediation Board; consultant, National Wage Stabilization Board; chairman Regional Enforcement Commission, National Wage Stabilization Board; served as arbitrator in shipbuilding, textile, restaurant, food, retail department stores, baking, aluminum, machinery, chemical, paper, radio, public utilities, fur, aircraft, steel and many other industries.
Affiliated with the Industrial Relations Research Association; National Academy of Arbitrators (vice president and former member of Board of Governors); New York and American Bar Associations; former chairman, Committee on Labor and Social Security Legislation, New York City Bar Association; former chairman, Labor Law Section, New York City Bar Association.
Umpire for Bethlehem Steel Co. and Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers, 1949-60; impartial chairman, Publishers Association of New York and Newspaper and Mail Deliverers Union of New York and Vicinity, 1949-50; impartial chairman, Marine Engineers Beneficial Association and American Merchant Marine Institute, 1955-; Impartial Chairman International Typographical Workers Union and N.Y. Post, 1963-; Impartial Chairman, Phelps Dodge Corporation and United Steelworkers of America 1961-; Impartial Chairman, Associated Fur Manufacturers, Inc. and Furriers Joint Council of New York City, 1968-75.
Died Aguust 5, 1975.
Scope and Contents
Includes over 2500 arbitration awards, decisions and related documents for cases arbitrated primarily in the industries of steel, fur, electronics, transportation, construction, chemicals, aluminum, retail trade, entertainment, television, publishing, wholesale and retail food, paper, shipbuilding, textiles, baking, machinery, and aircraft. Also include arbitration cases in civil service, public education, and public utilities.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Absenteeism -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Alcohol abuse -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Aircraft industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Airlines -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Aluminum industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Bakers and bakeries -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Brewing industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Chemical industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Civil service -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Construction industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Container industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Education -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Electronic industries -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Entertainment industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Food industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Food service -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Foundries -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Fur trade -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Glass manufacture -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Grocery trade -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Insurance companies -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Machine industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Metal-workers -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Newspaper publishing -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Paper industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Printing industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Public utilities -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Publishing -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Radio broadcasting -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Retail trade -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Shipbuilding industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Steel industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Teachers -- New York (State) -- New York; Arbitration, Industrial -- Telecommunication -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Television broadcasting -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Textile industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Transportation -- United States; Bargaining unit -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Bargaining unit -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Contracting out -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employee fringe benefits -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employee rights -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employees, Dismissal of -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employees, Training of -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employees, Transfer of -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Grievance procedures -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Grievance procedures -- Shipbuilding industry -- United States; Grievance procedures -- Steel industry -- United States; Hours of labor -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Industrial equipment -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Industrial safety -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Job security -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Job vacancies -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Labor discipline -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Labor productivity -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Layoffs -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Management rights -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Misconduct -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Supplementary employment -- United States; Vacations, Employee -- Law and legislation -- United States; Performance appraisal -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Position classification -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Promotions -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Retirement -- Law and legislation -- United States; Seniority, Employee -- Law and legislation -- United States; Seniority, Employee -- Law and legislation -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Aluminum industry -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Fur trade -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Machine industry -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Printing industry -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Shipbuilding industry -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Steel industry -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Telecommunication -- United States; Labor unions -- Recognition -- United States; Union security -- Law and legislation -- United States; Fur workers -- Labor unions -- United States -- Jurisdictional disputes; Unfair labor practices -- United States; Wages -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Wages -- Fur trade -- United States; Wages -- Shipbuilding industry -- United States; Wages -- Steel industry -- United States; Work assignments -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employee rules -- United States; Working conditions -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Feinberg, I. Robert (Irving Robert), 1912-1975; Seward, Ralph T. (Ralph Theodore), 1907-; Wallen, Saul, 1910-1969; A. Neustadter and Sons, Inc.; ACF Industries, Inc. American Car and Foundry Division; ACF Industries, Inc.; Actors' Equity Association; Allied Maintenance Company; Aluminum Company of America; American Cyanamid Company; American Federation of Teachers; American Newspaper Guild; Armstrong Cork Company; Associated Actors and Artistes of America; Associated Fur Manufacturers; Ben Eskind, Inc.; Ben Preffer Company; Berger and Savage, Inc.; Bethlehem Steel Corporation; Bloomingdale's (Firm); Building Service Employees' International Union; Carrier Corporation; Celanese Corporation of America; City University of New York; City University of New York. Legislative Conference; Clay Furs, Inc.; Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.; Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America; Communications Workers of America; Continental Can Company; Daily Mirror; Dan Grossman Company; David Soifer Furs, Inc.; Debutante Furs, Inc.; Directors' Guind of America; E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company; Empire State Telephone Union; Perth Amboy Wharf (N.J.); Fourrures Sport Walt Stiel Ltd; Furriers Joint Council of New York; General Electric Company; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; Insurance Workers International Union; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers; International Brotherhood of Paper Makers; International Chemical Workers Union; International Typographical Union. No. 6 (New York, N.Y.); International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers; International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers; International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (A.F. of L.); Irving Hans, Inc.; Irving Katz Company; J. & L. Kessler, Inc.; Lazar and Wisotzky, Inc.; League of Off-Broadway Theaters and Producers; Lehigh Portland Cement Company; M. Reiner and Sons, Inc.; Mack Manufacturing; Marle Harris, Inc.; Maximillan Fur Company; Morris and Sons, Inc.; National Sugar Refining Company; National Union Radio Corporation; New York (N.Y.). Board of Education; New York Mailers' Union; New York Papercutters' and Bookbinders' Union; New York Post Corporation; New York Printing Pressmen's Union; New York Telephone Company; New York Times Company; Newspaper and Mail Deliverers' Union of New York City and Vicinity; Newspaper Guild of New York; Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union; Parlin Employees' Association, Inc.; Philip Winick Fur Corporation; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company; Pratt & Whitney Aircraft Group; Prudential Insurance Company of America; Radio Writers Guild; Radley Furs, Inc.; Reigel Paper Corporation; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; Rochester Telephone Corporation (Rochester, N.Y.); Seaboard World Airlines; Seidler Brothers; Sidney Lambert, Inc.; Sperry Rand Corporation; Transport Workers Union of America; United Cement, Lime and Gypsum Workers International Union; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America; United Federation of Teachers; United Packinghouse Workers of America; United Papermakers and Paperworkers; United Press International; United Steelworkers of America; United Sugar Refinery Workers; West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company; Western Electric Company; William Rosenfeld, Inc.; World Telegram
3336821
- Brewster Aeronautical Corp. and UAW, Local 365 CIO. 4/12/46 [File A&B], 1946 (Box 1, Folder 485)
  Scope and Contents
  Decision: Discharge; Super seniority. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Famous Studios and Screen Cartoonists, Local 1461 AFL. 5/14/46, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 495)
  Decision: Back pay award; Rates of pay; Training and trial periods. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- American Pharmaceutical Co., Inc. and Manufacturing, Wholesale and Retail Employees Council of Greater New York and Vicinity, Local 22658 AFL. 7/1/46, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 525)
  Decision: Rates of pay; Salary schedule. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and collective agreements.
- Ideal Roller and Manufacturing Co., Inc. and IAM, Dist. 15, Lodge 295. 7/9/46, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 539)
  Decision: Incentive pay and incentive systems in relation to temporary transfers. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Cleaning Contractors Corp. and BSEIU, Local 32J AFL. 11/14/46, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 577)
  Decision: Union representatives and business; Union security; Checkoff; Vacation pay. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Camburn, Inc. and UE, Local 430, CIO. 2/27/47. [Files A&B], 1947 (Box 1, Folder 616)
  Decision: Rates of pay; Retroactive pay. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements and exhibits.
- New York Water Service Corp. and South Bay Consolidated Water Co., Inc. and UWU, Local Union 355 CIO. 4/11/47 [File 1008-AD], 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1008)
  Decision: Rates of pay; Equalization; Union security; Holiday pay. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits. This case affords a good look at the interplay between wage rates and the CPI. Much information re the above i
- Canada Dry Ginger Ale, Inc. and American Federation of Office Employees, Local 20940. 3/26/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1010)
  Decision: Back pay award; Inability to work; Strikes, slowdowns and work stoppages. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Harry Kazan Linoleum Co. and Retail Furniture and Floor Covering Employees, Local 853, CIO. 4/11/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1011)
  Decision: Discharge; Improper job attitude. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Grey Advertising Agency and United Office and Professional Workers Union, Local 20, CIO. 4/16/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1012)
  Decision: Discharge; Incompetence and inefficiency. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- Eastern Furniture Mfg. Co. and Furniture Workers Union, Local 76B. 4/17/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1015)
  Decision: Discharge, Removal of work from bargaining unit. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and collective agreements.
- Coca-Cola Bottling Co. of NY, Inc. and Soft Drink Workers Union, Local 812., 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1016)
  [File A] 5/2/47. Decision: Discharge; Dishonesty; Negligence and carelessness. Contains personal notes and correspondence. [File B] 12/28/48. Decision: Suspension; Negligence and carelessness. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Hall Anderson Co. and Furniture Workers' Union, Local 76-B. 5/8/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1018)
  Decision: Vacation pay; Termination of business. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and collective agreements.
- United Parcel Service, Inc. and IBT, Local 177, AFL. 5/16/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1019)
  Decisions: Discharge, intoxication; Back pay award, tardiness. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and collective agreements.
- United Parcel Service of NY and IBT, Local 804. 5/29/47 [Files A&B], 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1021)
  Decision: Plant rules re dress (union buttons); Management rights. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Miles Shoes, Inc. and Wholesale and Warehouse Workers Union, Local 65., 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1022)
  [File A] 5/29/47. Decision: Discharge; Improper job attitude; Insubordination. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits. [File B] 10/26/48. Decision: Discharge; Improper job attitude; Insubordination. Contains person
- Volco Brass & Copper Co. and Int'l Union of Mine, Mill & Smelter Workers, Local 673. 6/3/47, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1023)
  Decisions: 1) Discharge; Absence; Medical release. 2) Supervisors and Foremen, Removal of work from bargaining unit. 3) Super seniority. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Antipyros Co. and Antipyros Employees Assn. Inc. 7/6/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1024)
  Decision: Discharge; Improper job attitude; Improper personal conduct; Improper work practices. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- R.H. Macy & Co. and RWDSU, Local 1-S. 12/47 [File A&B], 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1028)
  Decision: Transfers; Testing of employees. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and c.
- National Urn Bag Corp. and Wholesale and Warehouse Workers Union, Local 65, CIO. 7/16/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1029)
  Decision: Contract modification; rates of pay. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- National Automotive Parts Assn., NY Warehouse, Inc. and RCIA, Local 1146 AFL. 7/15/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1033)
  Decision: Discharge; Reduction in force; Union representatives and business. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- Lecody Toasted Pie Co. and BCW, Local 3, AFL. 7/23/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1034)
  Decision: Contract interpretation; Vacation and vacation pay. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Hanscom Baking Co. and BCW, Local 50. 8/15/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1035)
  Decision: Vacations and vacation pay; Strikes; slowdowns, and work stoppages. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- Bronx Home News Publishing Co. and Newspaper Guild of NY, CIO. 11/12/47 [Files A&B], 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1037)
  Decisions: 1) Reinstatement. 2) Schedules of work; Overtime premium pay. 3) Classification of jobs. 4) Temporary employees; Recall. 5) Back pay award; Classification of jobs. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits
- American Hard Rubber Co. and URW, c 36 CIO. 9/2/47, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1038)
  Decision: Layoff; Incompetence and inefficiency.
- New York City Realty Advisory Board and BSEIU, Local 219 c. 1947-8 [Files A-D], 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 1039)
  Decision: Rates of pay (19 cases, same issues and parties). Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- G.W. Carnrick Co. and UMW, District 50, Local 12189. 9/13/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1042)
  Decision: Holidays & holiday pay. Contains personal notes, correspondence and exhibits.
- Eastern Novelty Mirror Manufacturers Assn., Inc. and Novelty Mirror Workers Union, Local 7. 8/19/47 (Box 2, Folder 1043)
  Decision: Rates of pay. Contains personal notes, and correspondence.
- Borden's Farm Products and IBT, Local 602. 10/1/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1044)
  Decisions: 1) Management's rights in regard to filling vacancies. 2) Discharge of handicapped employees. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Pinkerton's National Detective Agency, Inc. and Independent Assn. of Racetrack Police. 10/13/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1045)
  Decision: Discharge; Improper work practices. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- S.M. Fields and Co., Inc. and United Photographic Employees Union, Local 415, CIO. 10/14/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1046)
  Decision: Discharge; Improper job attitude; Improper personal conduct; Improper work practices. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Brewers Board of Trade, Ind. And Int'l Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal and Soft Drink Workers of America. 10/28/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1047)
  Decision: Discharge; Improper work practices; Improper job attitude. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- United Restaurant & Liquor Dealers of Manhattan, Inc. and Bartenders Union of NYC, Local 15. 10/30/47 [Files A&B], 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1048)
  Decision: Contract interpretation; Contract modification; Welfare funds. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Waldes Koh-I-Noor, Inc. and UE, Local 1227. 10/16/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1049)
  Decision: vacation pay (in regard to layoffs). Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- A. Finkenberg's Sons, Inc. and Retail Furniture and Floor Covering Employees Union, Local 853. 11/29/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1050)
  Decision: Rates of pay. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- Queens Bifocal Co., Inc. and United Optical Workers Union, Local 208. 11/13/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1051)
  Decision: Contract negotiation. Contains personal notes, correspondence, collective agreements, and exhibits.
- Ward Baking Company and Bakery Drivers Union, Local 550. 11/4/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1052)
  Decision: Discharge; Incompetence and inefficiency; Negligence and carelessness; Safety. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- 1352 Corp. operating "Monte Carlo" and Waiters and Waitresses Union, Local 1. 10/31/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1053)
  Decision: Discharge; Improper job attitude; Improper personal conduct; Improper work practices. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Farrand Optical Works and UE, CIO. 12/4/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1055)
  Decision 1) Equipment and physical facilities; Union representatives and business. 2) Supervisors and foremen; Classification of jobs. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and union exhibits.
- Charles Schaefer Corp. and Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal and Soft Drink Workers of America, Local 3. 12/18/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1057)
  Decision: Retroactive pay; Inability of employer to pay. Contains personal notes, and correspondence.
- S. Froelich Co., Inc. and Wholesale and Warehouse Workers Union, Local 65, CIO. 12/20/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1058)
  Decision: Contract negotiations. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- Port Chester Iron Works, Inc. and IBT. Local 456. 12/16/47, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1059)
  Decision: Discharge; Incompetence and inefficiency; Insubordination. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits.
- Joe Lowe Corp. and IBT, Local 138. 1/12/48, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1062)
  Decision: Discharge; Assignment of new jobs; Insubordination. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Meadow Gold Products Corp. and IBT, Local 757. 1/22/48, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1066)
  Decision: Reduction in force. Contains personal notes, correspondence, and exhibits
- Childs Co. and Chain Service Restaurant Employees Union, Local 42. 1/6/48, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1067)
  Decision: Discharge; Theft; Improper work practices. Contains personal notes and correspondence.
- Roberts Numbering Machine Co. and UE Local 1217 CIO. 2/20/48, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1069)